<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Take it up and read</title>
    <link>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Take it up and read</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://takeitupandread.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sing the Psalms</title>
      <link>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/sing-the-psalms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/sing-the-psalms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Or “Did God really say we should sing the psalms?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Open Bible&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://takeitupandread.com/images/2024/open-bible-sunlight.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining the sound team of a modern evangelical church can range from just clicking through YouTube videos (simple) to overseeing an entire music production, requiring in-depth technical skills and the ability to do live mixing (complicated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you find yourself somewhere in the middle of that spectrum, you might be tasked with the following responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure all the cables are plugged in correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn on the power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a sound check on the microphones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a sound check on the guitar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the preacher’s microphone is muted during singing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the volume levels are rightly adjusted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very simplified checklist, and for the most part the operations run smoothly because of lists like these and the faithful people who ensure that they are implemented Sunday after Sunday.
In short, this checklist is essentially our way of trying to ensure the best possible outcome in the context of singing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
