<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Take it up and read</title>
    <link>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Take it up and read</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://takeitupandread.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Redeeming post mission blues</title>
      <link>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2025/post-mission-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2025/post-mission-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a few thoughts on why we experience a dip in the degree to which we operate in the spirit after short term missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission-conditions-are-unique&#34;&gt;Mission conditions are unique&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When coming back from short term missions, the following things tend to change quite a bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fellowship of believers: on mission we are surrounded 24/7 by believers who are very zealous for the Lord.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less distractions: on mission we don&amp;rsquo;t have to concern ourselves with many of the day-to-day responsibilities we have back at home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prayers of other believers: on mission we have other believers constantly praying for us, especially if we make a point to organize prayer partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When these things fall away, the natural result is that we don&amp;rsquo;t experience the same spiritual walk in our daily lives as we had on the mission.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good death</title>
      <link>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/good-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/good-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a recent discussion with a friend, the topic of ‘death leading to life’ was brought up and how essential it is in the Bible.
In looking at what feels to me like a more and more lifeless world, the connection between the state of the world and this principle came to mind.
I believe that one of the biggest problems we have today, whether in politics, schools, family life, men, or women, is that there is a growing inability to produce life because of a growing unwillingness to die.
Where is no death, life cannot be brought forth, and those who most depend on others to die (citizens, children, spouses) suffer for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on life</title>
      <link>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/thoughts-on-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/thoughts-on-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I measure a culture according to its ability to create and sustain life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a conversation a few years ago, a friend of mine made this passing comment that has stuck with me ever since.
The implication is that a culture in which children, animals, and plants flourish is superior to one in which they don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since reflecting on this has been a blessing to me, I decided to write my thoughts down in case it might bless others as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sing the Psalms</title>
      <link>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/sing-the-psalms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://takeitupandread.com/blog/2024/sing-the-psalms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Or &amp;ldquo;Did God really say we should sing the psalms?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible has a very brief and simple checklist for what we are to sing as the Church.
Just one explicit command, and it’s given to us twice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;addressing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs&lt;/strong&gt;, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart&amp;rdquo; ~ Ephesians 5:19 (ESV, my emphasis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, &lt;strong&gt;singing psalms and hymns and spiritual songs&lt;/strong&gt;, with thankfulness in your hearts to God.&amp;rdquo; ~ Colossians 3:16 (ESV, my emphasis)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
